# **Mauricio Madrid**

Rio Rancho, NM 87144 • Home Ph.# (505)228-0545 • E-mail: mcmadrid66@outlook.com

## **Professional Summary**

Fifteen years' progressive experience in a high-tech manufacturing environment. Sixteen years' total experience as an Engineer. Engineering experience includes two years' as a Reliability Engineer, Three years' as a Mechanical Engineer, and Eleven years' as an Industrial Engineer

#### **Skills**

- Expertise in equipment performance evaluation and optimization, data mining via Database extractions/queries, direct observations, factory layout space optimization, resolving schedule conflicts
- Extremely Proficient analyzing, summarizing, and communicating operational performance data
- Computer Proficient with MS Office (Excel, Power Point, Outlook, Word), AutoCAD, TurboCAD, SAS software, SQL Pathfinder, JMP, Simulators, Visual Basic programming a.k.a. Visual Studio
- Demonstrated ability to learn complex tasks quickly, readiness to constantly learn, mentor, and assist

## **Work Experience**

Intel Corporation (Rio Rancho, NM)

9/2000 – 12/2015

**Industrial Engineer** - Responsible for tactical and strategic planning and performance, determining tool quantity, optimizing factory layout, supporting Lean Activities, Capital equipment optimization and utilization, and supporting upgrade, install, demo, relocation activities and schedule.

- o Responsible for \$250M of capital equipment Worldwide
- Analyzed and Improved entity metrics by 23% saving \$45M
- o Identified several metric parameters positively affecting tool performance by 14% closing the gap to 2% of model on record

**Process Manufacturing Technician** - Responsible for Engineering/Specialized processing in the field, addressing all process related issues, operator error, tool error and malfunctions, and continued process/yield improvements

- Critical in assisting engineers and other process technicians testing recipes and procedures which resulted in reducing tuning time by 25%.
- Demonstrated leadership through taking the initiative to support area priorities and mentoring new technicians to aid and assist obtaining their certifications

**Manufacturing Technician** – Responsible for successful operation of area and team module in meeting factory goals, processing of product, maintaining toolset and processes, training others, effective role modeling, area leader or mentor, and identifying, analyzing, and solving non-routine problems.

- o Identified and selected as best candidate for Process Control Manufacturing Tech Certification
- Working effectively with peers and engineering
- Able to obtain certification extremely quick leveraging formal education
- McNeil Consumer Healthcare, Johnson & Johnson Medical Inc. (Austin, TX)
  7/1998 1/1999
  Mechanical Engineer Responsible for supporting manufacturing activities, identifying equipment safety systems were functioning properly, contributing to site/building engineering support, and ownership of engineering projects in the field, validating and updating Standard Operating Procedures.
  - Aided in identifying a key component orientation to minimize down time by 50%.
  - Quickly and precisely determine and validate key equipment parameters in the field to document for use in production.

• **Self-Employed** (Las Cruces, NM)

1/1996 - 7/1998

**Reliability Engineer** – Analyzing equipment failure potential to determine preventative maintenance activities, extensive travel to analyze equipment in the field of operation, and analysis presentation to support new equipment purchases and spare parts inventory costs for further ROI analysis.

- Demonstrated excellent work ethic and ability to work in the field or in the office with no supervision or constant reminder to meet deadlines or get work done
- Able to effectively determine most productive use of resources or time management
- Data Collection, Analysis, and Reporting
- o Reliability Prediction, Confidence Intervals for MTBF
- Johnson & Johnson Medical Inc. (El Paso, TX)

7/1995 – 7/1996

**Mechanical/Reliability Engineer** – Site and manufacturing engineering support.

• Personal Time 1/2016 – Present

- Traveled extensively
- Personal Financial Portfolio up +67.2%
- Setup and configured home network and security systems
- Handyman jack of all trades (Personal property barrier fence install, clearing, and repair, house painting and closet organization, Auto repair, etc.)

## **Education**

• New Mexico State University, Las Cruces, NM. Bachelor of Science,

Major: Mechanical Engineering Technology

• New Mexico State University, Las Cruces, NM. Bachelor of Business Administration,

Major: Finance